Brian Davies

Full Stack React Developer Contact Information:

Phone: (647) 784-2069

Email: brian.davies589@gmail.com **Portfolio:** <u>github.com/sommcoder</u> **Location:** Toronto, Ontario, Canada

Professional Summary:

After more than 12 years in the Hospitality industry as a wine sommelier, I discovered my passion for software development while building my own wine club subscription business in response to the challenges posed by COVID-19. Proficient in CMS platforms for my business's website, I embarked on a journey of self-study, online courses, and personal projects to delve into the intricacies of web development. With extensive applied business experience, I offer a mature perspective, coupled with a diverse background in entrepreneurship, operations management, and e-commerce, underpinned by the determination forged through professional challenges.

Technical Skills:

Programming Languages: JavaScript (up to ES2023), some experience with TypeScript and Python (v3.12). **Domain-Specific Languages:** HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, SQL and Liquid (Shopify's templating language).

Libraries: React, React Router, React Query, jQuery, Styled-Components and Framer Motion.

Frameworks: Express and Fastify using the Node.js runtime.

Databases: PostgreSQL (Object-Oriented SQL) and MongoDB (Document based NoSQL).

Dev Tools: Github, Postman, Babel, Vite, WebPack, NPM, MongoDB Atlas, PgAdmin and VSCode. **Dev Ops:** Experience deploying to Google Cloud Platform and Firebase as well as using Docker.

System Design: Understanding of the SDLC as well as MVC, JAM, SPA, MPA, SSR and Island app architecture.

Portfolio Highlights:

1) JSSX - JSX to SuiteScript API Call Library:

- Uses the Babel Core API to parse JSX component hierarchies into an Abstract Syntax Tree. Babel traverses
 the tree and generates SuiteScript API calls for Suitelet development to be deployed on the NetSuite ERP.
- Using native SuiteScript API calls require verbose function calls that contain a lot of redundancy, repetition
 and are difficult to read and maintain as most Suitelet UIs can span well over 100 lines of code in an IDE. By
 using this library, developers are able to express the same Suitelet UI using 50% less code.

2) Mar-Key - Application for Testing Analogue Content Display:

- A full-stack application made specifically for Paradise Entertainment Corp that allows its employees to be able to plan and test analogue display messages that are destined to be added to their three marquees of varying size and character tile dimensions. Mar-key stores the inventory and dimensions of all of the physical character tiles and performs client side validation checks to assist users in visualising their desired analogue display before they attempt to manually set it up.
- Mar-key compares the current setup to the desired setup and indicates how many of each letter the
 employee will need to retrieve from storage. Though hyper-specific, this application cuts down on labour
 costs by avoiding trial-and-error attempts and having to rework content due to lack of inventory or available
 display space.

3) Wordle Clone - A Client-Side Clone of Wordle:

- This was my first app that I built all on my own. It's just a simple client-side copy of the popular New York Times app Wordle.
- No server or database functionality however I was able to replicate the Wordle CSS animations and got some familiarity using vanilla JavaScript and JQuery at the time.

Professional Experience:

Paradise Entertainment Corp. (1006a Bloor Street West, Toronto, Ontario, Canada)

Shopify ECommerce Manager

June 2022 - Current

- Facilitated the launch, creation of marketing material, customization of web pages and third party app integrations
- Was able to accurately and efficiently upload over 200 wine SKUs on Shopify.
- Solely responsible for the launch of our wine subscription program in Nov 2023 as well as the marketing material that we distributed in anticipation for launch.

Paradise Entertainment Corp. (1006a Bloor Street West, Toronto, Ontario, Canada)

Wine Director & Retail Manager

March 2023 - Nov 2023

- Promoted to Wine Director and Retail Manager, overseeing \$250,000+ worth of SKUs and managing a
 yearly purchasing budget exceeding \$500,000.
- Led two direct reports to achieve excellent customer service, loyalty and product knowledge.
- Implemented new sales channels, such as UberEats and our Shopify subscription program via Recharge.
- Increased revenue year over year by 30% and developed detailed recurring reports to stakeholders.

Paradise Entertainment Corp. (1006a Bloor Street West, Toronto, Ontario, Canada)

Sommelier & POS Administrator

March 2021 - March 2023

- Integrated POS with inventory management software, optimizing cost-of-goods-sold reporting.
- Contributed to establishing workplace procedures in purchasing, receiving, merchandising, POS programming, website UI design, inventory management, and business reporting.

Gravity Wine Company (38 Dan Leckie Way, Toronto, Ontario, Canada)

Sole-Proprietor

Nov 2020 - July 2022

- Founded a virtual wine service and subscription business, managing brand creation, website, and social media accounts.
- Successfully presented a virtual wine tasting experience to an audience of over 80 employees for a major international consulting firm.

Montecito Restaurant (299 Adelaide Street West, Toronto, ON, Canada)

Beverage Manager

April 2018 - October 2019

- Managed two wine programs with 250+ SKUs, leading day-to-day wine operations and staff training.
- Responsible for over \$200,000 worth of beverage products and weekly purchases exceeding \$15,000.

Colette Grand Café (550 Wellington Street West, Toronto, ON, Canada)

Sommelier & Operations Manager

August 2015 - February 2018

- Managed monthly purchasing budget of \$18,000+ in wine at 28-30% COGS.
- Maintained \$40,000 wine inventory with over 120 primarily French wines from eclectic regions.

Education:

JavaScript from Zero to Mastery	Jonas Schmedtmann (udemy.com)	March 2022
CS50x: Introduction to Computer Science	HarvardX (edx.org)	February 2022
Nodes.js, MongoDB, Express Bootcamp	Jonas Schmedtmann (udemy.com)	June 2022
Understanding TypeScript - 2023 Edition	Maximilian Schwarzmüller (udemy.com)	October 2022
Complete SQL Bootcamp - PostgreSQL	Jose Portilla (udemy.com)	November 2022
Wine and Spirit Education Trust Level 3	International Wine Education Guild (Toronto, ON	Sept 2013
Food and Beverage Management Diploma	George Brown College (Toronto, ON)	June 2012